A Guide to the Papers of Ann Beattie
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Ann Beattie 1985-1989
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10414-s
This collection consists of ca. 80 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was deposited 1989 August 2
Scope and Content Information
This collection contains typescripts of many Beattie short stories, magazine articles, and introductions; and typescript advance copies of several books with correspondence soliciting Beattie's review, including a letter, 1988 October 12, from Jacqueline Onassis requesting a review of Darcey Steinke's novel "Up through the water."
Contents List
- Short Stories
  - "Ed and Dave Visit the City," w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "Heaven, On A Summer Night" and "Times," w/cover letter from The New Yorker, 5 items 1986 Oct 30, TMs (Box 1)
  - "Home to Marie," w/corrections and cover letter from The New Yorker1986, Author's Proofs (Box 1)
  - "Horatio's Trick," w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "The Hotel Luna," w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "The Hotel Luna," w/corrections n.d., TMs electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - "In Amalfi" and "Taking Hold," w/corrections and cover letter from Fiction Network, 2 items 1986, TMss (Box 1)
  - "Janus," w/corrections and cover letter from The New Yorkerca. 1985 May, TMs (Box 1)
  - "Letters from Vienna," w/corrections, cover letter from Joan Harting of Elle, and a copy of an editorial letter in praise of AB's fiction ca. 1987 July 1, TMs (Box 1)
  - "Simple Things," w/corrections and cover letter from Tom Jenks of Gentlemen's Quarterly (GQ)1988 Jan 21, Galley Proofs (Box 1)
  - "Skeletons," w/corrections n.d., TMs electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - "The Sweetest Songs," early draft, w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "The Sweetest Songs," second draft(?), w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "Swimming Lessons," early draft w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "Swimming Lessons," second draft(?), w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "Tourists," first draft (?), w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "Tourists," second draft(?), w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - "Tourists," third draft(?) n.d., TMs electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - "Tourists," fourth draft(?) w/corrections and cover letter from Lisa Grunwald of Esquire 1988, TMs (Box 1)
  - Untitled, "At the Miami airport...," w/corrections n.d., TMs electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - Untitled, "If I Knew how to climb rocks...," w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - Untitled, "Joel Meyerowitz is good...," w/corrections, 2 items n.d., TMs electrostatic copies (Box 1)
  - Untitled, "Meyerowitz shows...," w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - Untitled, "Taking the puppy...," w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
  - Untitled, "The morning Christine Darden...," w/corrections n.d., TMs (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous Manuscripts
  - Ann Beattie introduction, The Best American Short Stories 1987, w/corrections ca. 1987, TMs (Box 1)
  - Ann Beattie introduction, The Best American Short Stories 19871987 Jun, Page Proofs (Box 1)
  - Ann Beattie introduction, The Best American Short Stories 1987, w/corrections and cover letter from Larry Cooper, Houghton Mifflin Company 1987 Jun 11, Page Proofs (Box 1)
  - Ann Beattie introduction to Sally Mann's At Twelve: Portraits of Young Women, w/corrections, ca. 1987-1988, TMssS electrostatic copies (Box 1)
  - Ann Beattie introduction to Sally Mann's At Twelve: Portraits of Young Women, w/corrections 1988, Page Proofs (Box 1)
  - "Ann Beattie Visits The Walt Whitman Mall," early incomplete draft, w/corrections 1988 Mar/Apr, TMs (Box 1)
  - "Ann Beattie Visits The Walt Whitman Mall," corrected draft (formerly "The Walt Whitman Mall") ca. 1988, TMsS electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - "Ann Beattie Visits The Walt Whitman Mall," w/corrections and annotations ca. 1988, TMs electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - "Ann Beattie Visits The Walt Whitman Mall," w/corrections ante 1988 Jul 4, Galley Proofs (Box 1)
  - "Ann Beattie Visits The Walt Whitman Mall," w/corrections and cover letter from John Atwood, Long Island Monthly1988 Jul 4, Galley Proofs (Box 1)
  - "Ann Beattie Visits The Walt Whitman Mall," w/cover letter from John Atwood, Long Island Monthly 1988 Jul 19, Layout electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - Articles(?) re Barbados, w/corrections, 2 items n.d., TMs (Box 1)
- Letters and Miscellaneous
  - Letters from editors and publishers soliticiting Ann Beattie's review of upcoming publications 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    Includes an October 12, 1988 letter from Jacqueline Kennedy Onassis of Doubleday.
  - Writers Conference, Santa Monica College, California (AB as a featured writer) 1987, Poster (Box 1)
- Advanced Reading Copies for Ann Beattie's Review
  - Sudden Fiction: American Short Stories: "Introduction" and "Afterwords" ca. 1986, Electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - Only One: The Special Experience of the Only Child by Ellie McGarth w/postcard from Marie Guarnaschelli, William Morrow & Co., Inc. 1988 August, TMs electrostatic copy (Box 1)
  - Bicycle Days by John Burnham Schwartz, w/cover letter from Ileene Smith, Summit Books 1988 Oct, TMs electrostatic copy (Box 2)
  - What I Have to Tell You by Mary Elsie Robertson, w/cover letter from Jennifer Brehl, Doubleday 1989 Feb, TMs electrostatic copy (Box 2)
  - The Setting Sun and the Rolling World by Charles Mungoshi, w/cover letter from Deborah Chasman, Beacon Books 1989 Mar, Page Proofs (Box 2)
  - Hairdo by Susan Gilbert ca. 1989, TMs electrostatic copy (Box 2)
  - World Sudden Fiction(Sampler) w/"Table of Contents" n.d., TMss electrostatic copies (Box 2)